<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Varna Tour Guide App</string>
    
    <string-array name="cites">
        <item>Yo-Ho-Hostel</item>
        <item>Hostel Del Mar</item>
        <item>X-Hostel</item>
        <item>Avocado Hostel</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="list_item_icon">list item icon</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <!-- Category name for phrases [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_museums">Museums</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for colors [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_accommodation">Sleep</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for numbers [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_culture">Culture</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for numbers [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_fun">Fun</string>
    <string name="avatar">avatar</string>
    <string name="yo_ho_hostel">Yo-Ho-Hostel</string>
    <string name="yoho_address">23, \"Russe\" Str.\nwww.yohohostel.com</string>
    <string name="yoho_description">Yo-Ho-Hostel - most popular place in the heart of Varna ! Hostel for backpackers, explorers, musicians and artists ! OPEN ALL YEAR ROUND AND 24/7 !
        Yo-Ho-Hostel - 12th Years we offer you the BEST PRICE in Varna ! Come, check and stay longer than you expect!
        Most central, most friendly, most funny …

        Top rated hostel in Varna since 2007 from www.hostelworld.com! Sleep Easy !
        Best recommended hostel in Varna from \'Lonely Planet\' Guide Book 2008, 2009 ,2011 and 2015 !
        The only hostel in Varna recommended from \'Le Guide du Routard\' from 2008 till 2016 !
        Where are we on the map?
        Walking distance from Yo-Ho-Hostel you can find:
        -Tourist information center – 1 minute walk
        -Cathedral church – 2 minutes walk
        -Theater and Opera – 2 minutes walk
        -Pedestrian street – 2 minutes walk
        -Railway station – 8 minutes walk
        -Archeological Museum – 8 minutes walk
        -Black Sea and Central beach– 15 minutes walk
        -Bus Station – 20 minutes walk
        Yo-Ho-Hostel is the most central place for accommodation in Varna! Every young and alternative looking person in the city can tell you where Yo-Ho-Hostel is situated. The address is 23, Ruse Street and here you will see a colorful door with a lot of graffiti art \' this is Yo-Ho-Hostel! Our GPS coordinates are: 43*12.216 N , 027*54.619 E
        You can use :
        -fully equipped self-catering kitchen
        -laundry and drying service
        -iron and ironing board
        -relaxing quiet garden
        -BBQ
        -Bar
        -Smoking area
        -Board games area
        -Exchange library
        -Guide books for hire
        - Bikes for hire
        - Table football and Arcanoid game
        - Security camera control
        OUR BATHROOMS ARE COMBO WITH WC
        If you don\'t like boring places!
        We will always give you an option to do something fun and interesting.
        For travelers, who like cultural activities you can find:
        -guided trips around Varna museums and art galleries
        -guided day trips to more than 20 interesting natural and historical sites
        -visiting Varna film, music and cultural festivals
        For alternative backpackers:
        -Bungy jumping from a 52 m high bridge
        -Boat trip with pirate’s ship “Pinta Varna” with fishing on the way
        -SCUBA diving for beginners and professionals
        -Kite, wind, long and skim board surfing close to Varna
        -Once per year - 3 days kayaking trip with sleeping in tents
        -Pub crawl in summer time
        -visiting of hot mineral springs in ' St. Constantine'

        This is the ONLY hostel where every night you can enjoy live music and meet some of the best musicians, artists and sports people from Bulgaria - exchanging interesting experiences with them. On arrival we require 10 BGN ( 5 EU ) key deposit.
        We will recommend you the best places to eat in Varna -Traditional Bulgarian, Turkish, Greek, Armenian, Italian, Spanish, Japanese and Fish restaurants. We are working with the best bars and clubs- you will be welcome like a V.I.P. there ! We are in perfect relation with our friends hostels in Bulgaria!
        Sozopol: Yo-Ho-Hostel - summer hostel
        Veliko Tarnovo: Hostel Mostel
        Sofia: Art Hostel -Usually we spend our time in the garden
        Sofia: Hostel Mostel
        Plovdiv: Hostel Old Plovdiv
        Burgas: Hostel A16
        Ruse: The English Guest house

        This is Yo-Ho-Hostel - culture and alternative, obligatory place for every backpacker who wants to explore Varna, Bulgaria!

        Welcome aboard!</string>
    <string name="description">Description:</string>
</resources>
